&gt;&gt; Hello, I'm Tanya Kancheva and
&gt;&gt; 大家好 我是 Tanya Kancheva
I'm here to talk about wireless
我在这里向大家介绍
CarPlay.
无线 CarPlay
wireless CarPlay is perfect for
无线 CarPlay 对于任何旅行而言
any trip, you can get in your
都是完美的 你可以直接进入到车中
car without taking your iPhone
不需要把你的 iPhone
out of your bag or pocket and
从包里或者口袋里拿出来
start experiencing CarPlay
就能够开始毫不费劲地体验 CarPlay
The CarPlay experience is the
无论你是用线缆连接
same whether you are plugged in
还是在无线状态下使用
or using it wirelessly.
CarPlay 的体验都是完全相同的
In this session, we will dive
在本场会议 我们会深入探讨
into the details on developing a
关于开发一个
wireless CarPlay system.
无线 CarPlay 系统的细节
First, let's start by talking
首先 让我们来谈一谈
about the wireless CarPlay
无线 Carplay
experience.
的体验
The first time you use wireless
第一次使用无线
CarPlay you need to pair your
CarPlay 的时候 你需要将
iPhone to your car.
iPhone 和你的车进行配对
The simplest way to pair is by
进行配对最简单的方法就是
plugging in iPhone using a
将 iPhone 接入你的车
cable.
通过一根线缆
You can also pair without
你也可以不用接入配对
plugging in by using the car's
通过使用车上的
UI to add a new device and by
交互界面来添加一个新设备
following the onscreen
并遵从屏幕上的
instructions.
指示
Plugging in iPhone using a cable
将 iPhone 通过线缆与车连接
is the easiest and fastest way
是最简单和最快速的方式
to pair for wireless CarPlay and
来配对无线 CarPlay
all wireless CarPlay systems
并且所有的无线 CarPlay 系统
should support this feature.
应该都支持这一特性
When iPhone is plugged in
当 iPhone 接入的时候
CarPlay starts normally.
CarPlay 会正常启动
If the car supports wireless
如果这辆车支持
CarPlay the user will be
无线 CarPlay
presented with the following
用户会在 iPhone 上看到如下的
prompt on iPhone.
提示
A simple tap on enable wireless
简单地轻点一下 “启用无线 Carplay ”
CarPlay completes the pairing
就能完成配对
process.
过程
Be sure to provide a meaningful
请确保提供一个有实际意义的
display name as in this example,
显示名称 例如在这个示例中
my car, so it's clear that
“我的车” 所以很明确
iPhone will be associated with
iPhone 会与这辆车
the car.
相连接
Once pairing is complete CarPlay
一旦配对完成
starts automatically the next
CarPlay 会在你下次进到车中时
time you enter the car.
自动启动
It's not necessary to require
不再需要
additional confirmation on the
在车载显示器上做额外的确认过程
car's display because CarPlay is
因为 CarPlay
already running and the user has
已经在运行了 并且用户
already chosen to use wireless
已经在 iPhone 上选择使用
CarPlay on iPhone.
无线 CarPlay
As you can see, pairing by
正如你们所见 通过
plugging in is simple and
连接设备来配对是非常简单
effortless.
且毫不费力的
The user can also pair without
用户也可以不用
plugging in and by using the
连接设备而是通过
car's UI to add a new device and
车内的交互界面来添加新设备
by following the onscreen
并遵循屏幕上的
instructions.
指示
To begin, the pairing process
首先 配对过程
needs to be started on both the
需要同时在
car and on iPhone.
车辆和 iPhone 上开始
To make it easier CarPlay
为了让过程变得更简单一些
standardizes a long press on the
CarPlay 规定了通过长按
Voice Control button to start
Voice Control 按钮来开始
the pairing process.
配对过程
Normally this will start Siri,
通常这样做会开启 Siri
but if no phone is connected the
但如果没有手机连接的话
car should immediately prepare
车辆会立即做好
for pairing.
配对的准备
You can also use menus and
你同样可以使用
settings in the car's native UI
车内原始用户界面
to start the pairing process.
来开始配对过程
You may offer a CarPlay specific
你们可以提供一个专门用于 CarPlay 的菜单
menu, a general Bluetooth menu
一个通用蓝牙菜单
or both.
或者两者都提供
In CarPlay settings on iPhone
在 iPhone 内的 CarPlay 设置中
users are encouraged to press
用户可以通过
and hold the Voice Control
按住方向盘上的 Voice Control 按钮
button on the steering wheel to
来开始
start the pairing process.
配对过程
Once CarPlay setup is started on
一旦 CarPlay 设置在
the car and iPhone select the
车辆和 iPhone 上都已开始
discovered device to start the
选择已发现的设备来开始
pairing process.
配对过程
Apple recommends that you allow
Apple 建议你们允许用户
the user to select the car from
在他们的 iPhone 上
iPhone.
选择车辆
In your native UI simply show
在你的原始界面只要显示出
your car's display name so the
车辆的名称
user knows what to look for.
用户就会知道他们应该去找哪一个设备
If you do allow the user to
如果你们允许用户
initiate selection from the car
在车内选择设备
you can show a list of
你们可以给出一个
discovered devices.
被发现设备的名单
You can show a less specific to
你也可以只显示出一个更短的特定名单
adding a CarPlay device or you
来添加一个 CarPlay 设备 或者你
can show a list of all
显示出一个
discovered Bluetooth devices,
所有被发现的蓝牙设备的名单
including CarPlay devices.
包括 Carplay 设备
If the user selects a device
如果用户选择了一个
using a general Bluetooth menu
使用通用蓝牙菜单的设备
and that device supports
并且那个设备支持
wireless CarPlay, you may decide
无线 CarPlay 你可以
to offer to enable CarPlay.
提供启用 CarPlay 的选项
Do not show this screen if the
如果用户从
user selected the device from a
CarPlay 特定菜单选择了设备的话
CarPlay specific menu.
不要让这一屏的内容显示出来
Then CarPlay connects and
那么之后 CarPlay 就会连接
CarPlay appears on the screen.
并且 CarPlay 会在屏幕上显示出来
From here on the CarPlay
之后的 CarPlay
experience is the same as
体验是与将 iPhone 通过线缆连接
plugging in until you leave the
完全一样的 直到你离开
car.
车辆
Every time the user enters the
每当用户进入车辆
car CarPlay reconnects
CarPlay 都会自动
automatically, iPhone can remain
重新连接
in your bag or pocket and no
iPhone 可以留在你的包里或是口袋里
user interaction is necessary.
不需要任何的用户操作
When CarPlay starts, be sure to
当 CarPlay 启动时 请一定
observe the last user mode for
检查在屏幕上用户最后使用的
audio in the display.
音频模式
For details, watch the video
了解更多细节的话 请观看视频
Developing CarPlay Systems Part
开发 CarPlay 系统
1.
第一部分
With wireless CarPlay it's easy
有了无线 CarPlay
to pair more than one iPhone
就可以很简单地
with the car.
将不止一部 iPhone 与车辆配对
In addition, you may have one or
另外 你也可以用线缆将一部或者
many iPhones plugged in at the
很多部 iPhone
same time.
同时连接
Provide a device selector in
在你的原始用户界面中
your native UI that lets the
请提供一个设备选择器
user choose the active CarPlay
来让用户选择活跃的 CarPlay
device.
设备
Once CarPlay has started don't
一旦 CarPlay 启动后
automatically switch to another
请不要自动切换到另一台
device.
设备
Changing the active CarPlay
更换活跃的 CarPlay
device should be an explicit
设备应该是由
user action.
用户决定的
If you support multiple
如果你支持多个
Bluetooth devices and have a
蓝牙设备并且
concept of favorite or
有偏好设备
frequently used devices use the
或者常用设备的设置
same mechanism for wireless
请将同样的机制使用在
CarPlay.
无线 CarPlay 上
Your device selector shows all
你的设备选择器会显示出所有的
CarPlay devices whether they are
CarPlay 设备 不论它们是
plugged in or paired for
通过线缆连接或是通过
wireless CarPlay.
无线 CarPlay 配对的
Indicate the active CarPlay
请通过使用 CarPlay 图标
device using the CarPlay logo.
指示出活跃的 CarPlay 设备
Never indicate if CarPlay is
请不要指示出 CarPlay 是
running over wireless or wired.
在有线或是无线模式下运行
The transfer type should be
传输模式
transparent to the user.
对于用户而言应该是完全清楚的
If you provide on off settings
如果你提供开关设置
don't provide separate settings
不要针对有线和无线 Carplay
for wired and wireless CarPlay,
分别提供设置
just provide a setting for
只需要提供一个
Bluetooth or iPod versus
蓝牙或者 iPod
CarPlay.
对 CarPlay 的设定
Be judicious in showing
显示通知的时候
notifications, only show
要明智一些 只显示
notifications when it's
重要到确实需要用户了解的
important to let the users know.
通知
Show a subtle notification when
当第一台 iPhone 连接之后
the first iPhone is connected
如果 CarPlay 没有
only if CarPlay will not
马上出现
immediately become visible or
或者 CarPlay 入口图标没有
the CarPlay [inaudible] icon is
马上出现时
not immediately visible.
请显示一个巧妙的通知
Show a notification when a
当第二台 iPhone 通过
second iPhone is connected over
USB 连接 并且 Carplay 仍在运行时
USB while CarPlay is running.
请显示一个通知
Do not show notifications when
当 iPhone 加入或者离开
iPhone joins or leaves the
接入点的时候 或者当它
access point or when it is
通过蓝牙重新连接时
reconnected over Bluetooth.
请不要显示通知
Now that we have seen how to use
既然我们已经看过如何使用
wireless CarPlay let's explore
无线 CarPlay 让我们来探索一下
what it takes to develop such a
开发这样一个系统
system.
需要做些什么
We'll start with the hardware
我们将从
requirements, go through setup
硬件要求入手 之后是关于 Carplay 的
and pairing, reconnecting for
设置和配对 重新连接
CarPlay, and finish with some
最后以一些
considerations for your wireless
有关无线结构的想法
architecture.
来结束
So, hardware requirements.
那么来谈谈硬件要求
wireless CarPlay requires
无线 CarPlay 需要
Bluetooth, a Wi-Fi access point
蓝牙  一个 Wi-Fi 接入点
and location data.
和位置信息
Bluetooth is used to discover
蓝牙用于发现
and reconnect CarPlay devices.
和重新连接 CarPlay 设备
To accomplish this the Bluetooth
要完成这一点  蓝牙子系统
subsystem needs to implement the
需要执行
Bluetooth core specification, as
蓝牙技术核心规范
well as support service
并且支持设备的发现
discovery, iAP2 protocols and
iAP2 协议
advertise CarPlay support in its
并在其扩展蓝牙查询响应中
Bluetooth Extended Inquiry
显示出对 CarPlay 的支持
The Wi-Fi link is used for all
Wi-Fi 连接被用于所有
audio and video transfer to the
对 Carplay 协议的音频和视频的传输中
CarPlay protocol, as well as
也用于
iAP2 data transfer.
iAP2 协议数据传输
The access point must be
接入点必须是
certified by the Wi-Fi Alliance
由 Wi-Fi 联盟所认证的
and it is recommended that it
并且建议
supports the 802.11ac standard
支持 802.11ac 标准
and operates in the 5GHz
并在 5 GHz
frequency band.
频段下运行
In addition, the axis point
另外 接入点
needs to support the Apple
需要支持 Apple
Device Information Element and
设备信息元
the Interworking Information
以及
Element.
互联信息元
The location has always been
位置一直以来都是
required for CarPlay, but it
CarPlay 所需要的
becomes an absolute necessity
但对于无线 CarPlay 来说
with wireless CarPlay as the
它变成了绝对需求
driver's phone might be left in
因为驾驶员的手机有可能留在
a pocket or a bag and be
口袋里或者包里
completely out of sight.
完全不在视线范围内
To provide reliable and precise
为了提供可靠和精确的
location data, the head unit
位置信息 车载系统
needs a GNSS receiver, access to
需要有 GNSS（全球卫星导航系统）接收器
the speed sensor of the vehicle,
车辆速度传感器的接入权限
as well as the ability to
以及
provide dead reckoning position
提供 Dead Reckoning（航位推算）信息
information.
的功能
Okay, now that we have talked
好的 我们已经了解过了
through the basic hardware
基本的硬件需求
requirements let's talk about
让我们来讨论一下
set up and pairing for CarPlay.
CarPlay 的设置和配对
First, let's look at what
首先 我们来看一下
components are needed to set up
有哪些组成部分是必需的
wireless and wired CarPlay.
对于有线和无线 CarPlay 的构建而言
Of course, one or many USB
当然 一个或者多个
ports, a Wi-Fi access point,
USB 接口 一个 Wi-Fi 接入点
Bluetooth module, and an
蓝牙模块
instance of the CarPlay
实体 CarPlay
communication plugin are
通讯插件
required.
也是必需的
On ignition on or a head unit
在引擎开的状态下 或者车载系统重启时
restart the components need to
这些组成部分需要
be initialized and set up.
初始化并建立好
USBs ready for role swap and NCM
USB 要为有线 Carplay 准备好做 Role Swap（角色互换）
communication for wired CarPlay.
和 NCM 通讯
BT, Wi-Fi and networking for
蓝牙 Wi-Fi 和网络系统
wireless CarPlay.
用于无线 Carplay
Bonjour and the communication
Bonjour 服务 和通讯插件
plugin to enable CarPlay
用来启用 CarPlay
discovery.
搜索
When all those components are
当所有这些部分都设置好
set up the system is ready for
系统就准备好可以
CarPlay connection.
做 CarPlay 连接了
As we saw earlier, there are two
正如我们之前所见  有两种方式
ways to pair iPhone to the car.
将 iPhone 与车辆配对
If iPhone is plugged in using a
如果 iPhone 是通过线缆所连接的
cable out-of-band pairing is
cable 带外配对就会
triggered in the background.
在后台被触发
Otherwise, a Bluetooth pairing
否则 就需要
process is needed.
蓝牙配对
Setup over USB requires less
通过 USB 设置就不需要很多
user interaction and is the
用户操作
recommended setup procedure.
同时这是我们推荐的设置程序
Now let's dive into pairing over
现在让我们来深入了解
USB.
通过 USB 配对
As you see in the diagram, we
正如你们在图表中所见
have the essential head unit
我们将所有的重要车载部件
components on the left-hand side
显示在左边
and iPhone is displayed on the
iPhone 显示
right.
在右边
At this point, the system is
在此时 系统已经
fully booted and ready for
完全启动并已为
CarPlay.
CarPlay 做好准备
The head unit is showing the
当用户通过 USB 连接
native user interface as the
车载系统正显示
user connects over USB.
原始用户界面
A USB role switch follows and
USB Role Switch（角色转换）紧随其后
iPhone shows that CarPlay's
iPhone 会显示 CarPlay
connected.
已经连接
With the role switch the unit
随着 Role Switch（角色转换）
also establishes an iAP2 link
系统同样会建立一个 iAP2 协议连接
declaring support for all
对所有请求消息
necessary messages.
提供支持
While the CarPlay session is
当 CarPlay 会话
starting over USB iPhone asks
通过 USB 连接开始时 iPhone 会询问
the user to enable wireless
用户是否启用
CarPlay.
无线 CarPlay
With that CarPlay over USB is
这样一来 USB 连接 CarPlay
already active.
就已经激活了
So, iOS proceeds with setting up
iOS 会继续设置
the audio and video streams to
音频和视频流
show CarPlay in the car.
来在车内的 CarPlay 上显示
Now the user decides to enable
现在用户决定启动
wireless CarPlay.
无线 Carplay
After user confirmation iOS
在用户确认后 iOS
generates a Bluetooth link key
会生成一个蓝牙连接密钥
and sends it over iAP to the
并会将它通过 iAP 协议发送给
unit.
车载系统
The head unit saves the link key
车载系统会保存这一连接密钥
together with the device
同时还有
transport identifiers and stores
设备传输标识符 并将
this iPhone as a Bluetooth
这台 iPhone 保存为
paired device set up for
已为 Carplay 设置的
CarPlay.
配对蓝牙设备
Once the device is saved the
一旦设备被保存
head unit sends back a
车载系统会发回
confirmation and out-of-band
一个确认值 同时带外
pairing is complete.
配对完成
Let's review.
我们来回顾一下
Without out-of-band pairing the
如果没有带外配对
CarPlay session is established
CarPlay 会话是通过
over USB and is not interrupted.
USB 建立的 并且不会被打扰
There is no actual exchange over
在这一过程中
BT during this process.
并没有实际通过蓝牙做出的交换
The device needs to be stored as
设备需要被保存为
the last connected BT device or
最后连接的蓝牙设备
preferred device so that it can
或者是偏好设备
be reconnected later on.
使它能够在之后重新连接
Hence, a wireless CarPlay
因此无线 CarPlay 会话
session will start automatically
只会在一个点火循环之后
only after an ignition cycle as
也就是当司机回到车上时
the driver returns to the car.
自动开始
It's important to note that you
请记住 这非常重要
should not start wireless
当司机断开 USB 连接的时候
CarPlay when the driver
不能启动无线 Carplay
be just leaving the car.
她可能只是要离开车辆
Now that we have seen the USB
我们已经了解过
setup for wireless CarPlay let's
通过 USB 来设置无线 CarPlay
take a look at the second
那让我们来看一下第二种方式
method, pairing over Bluetooth.
通过蓝牙配对
There are a couple of ways to
在一辆车内
initiate Bluetooth pairing in a
有很多种方式可以
vehicle.
开启蓝牙配对
A long press on the Voice
长按方向盘上的
Recognition button on the
语音识别按钮
steering wheel or through the
或者通过
native UI.
原始用户界面都可以实现
And with the native UI there are
在原始用户界面内
two options.
有两个选择
A dedicated UI for adding a
一套为添加 Carplay 设备的
CarPlay device or through the
专用用户界面 或者通过
already existing UI for adding a
现有用户界面来添加
BT device.
蓝牙设备
Over the next couple of slides,
在接下来的几张幻灯片内
we will look into the
我们会深入了解
differences between these
这些配对方式的
pairing methods.
不同之处
No matter which of the three
无论这三种用户界面
pairing UIs was used by the
中的哪一种被用户用来
driver to initiate pairing the
发起配对
head unit becomes discoverable.
车载系统都会变为可发现状态
The driver also needs to open
司机同样需要开启 iPhone 上的
either Bluetooth settings or
蓝牙设置或者
CarPlay settings on iPhone to
CarPlay 设置
set iOS in a Bluetooth
来将 iOS 同样设置为
discoverable mode as well.
蓝牙可发现状态
Again, this is a very generic
这是一个非常通用的
representation of the fact that
描述介绍了
both the phone and the head unit
手机和车载系统
must be set into a discoverable
都必须被设定为
mode.
可发现状态
Now let's look at the different
现在我们来看一下
options on how to set up the
如何将车载系统设为
head unit into a discoverable
可发现模式的不同选择
mode and how to select which
以及如何选择
device to pair to.
配对哪一个设备
In this first variation, the
在第一种情况下
head unit simply asks the user
车载系统会让用户
to search for the car's name on
在 Carplay 内 或者
the CarPlay or BT settings menus
iPhone 上的蓝牙设置菜单上
on iPhone.
搜寻车的名字
The user enters this menu by
用户要进入到这个菜单
either navigating the native UI
可以通过原始用户界面导航
to add a new Bluetooth device or
来添加新蓝牙设备或者
by long pressing on the Voice
长按
Recognition button on the
方向盘上的
steering wheel.
语音识别按钮
iPhone discovers the car and
iPhone 会发现车辆
lists it.
并将其列出
The driver can then select the
司机可以在 iPhone 上选择
car on iPhone and iOS initiates
车辆同时 iOS 会发起一个
a Bluetooth pairing request.
蓝牙配对请求
This is the simplest and most
这是完成蓝牙配对
straightforward approach to
最简单也是
accomplish Bluetooth pairing.
最直接的途径
The second option is for the
第二种选择
driver to select the device from
是让司机在车辆原始界面
a list of available Bluetooth
可见蓝牙设备列表中
devices on the car's native
选择
interface.
设备
In this case, the head unit is
在这一场景下 车载系统
not only discoverable, but also
不仅处于可见状态
scans for BT devices.
也在搜索其他蓝牙设备
Exactly as in the previous
正如前一个选项
option, the driver enters this
司机要进入到这个菜单
menu by either navigating the
可以通过原始用户界面导航
native UI to add a new Bluetooth
来添加一个新蓝牙设备
device or by long pressing on
或者通过长按方向盘上的
the Voice Recognition button on
语音识别
the steering wheel.
按钮
Any BT capable device will be
所有支持蓝牙的设备都会
shown in this list, so the list
在这一列表内显示出来 所以
might or might not include
列表可能包含也可能不包含
CarPlay devices.
CarPlay 设备
That is why it is important to
这就是为什么请牢记
note that in this option any
在这一选项中
mention of Apple CarPlay on the
在用户界面中任何对于 Apple CarPlay 的提及
UI is not recommended.
都是不建议去做的
With this UI, the driver can
在这一用户界面内 用户可以
select the device to pair to
从原始用户界面内选择设备来配对
from the native UI or as before
或者像之前一样
on the device.
在设备上选择
The third option is very
第三种选项很相似
similar, however, this time the
然而 这一次
user is explicitly adding a new
用户很明确地要从原始用户界面
CarPlay device from the native
来添加
user interface.
Carplay 设备
The list shows only devices that
这一列表只显示
actually support wireless
真正支持无线 Carplay
CarPlay.
的设备
The head unit must use the Apple
车载系统必须使用 Apple
CarPlay Bluetooth EIR to
CarPlay 蓝牙 EIR（设备标识寄存器）
accomplish this filtering.
来完成这一过滤操作
Again, as before, the driver
重申一下 如同之前一样 用户
selects either on the car's UI
可以在车辆的用户界面内选择
or on device.
或者在设备上选择
After a device has been selected
在设备被选择之后
the head unit and iPhone
车载系统和 iPhone
complete Bluetooth secure simple
就完成了 Bluetooth-Secure-Simple Pairing（简易安全蓝牙配对）
pairing and connect IP over
并通过蓝牙连接 IP 地址
Bluetooth and the head unit
然后车载系统
identifies support for the
会识别出对于请求消息
required messages.
的支持
When iAP2 connects iOS will
当 iAP2 协议连接后 iOS
prompt the user to enable
会在设备上立刻提示用户来启用
wireless CarPlay on device.
无线 CarPlay
And just as a side note, but a
虽然这只是个边注
very important one, connect
但也非常重要
additional BT profiles only if
只有当无线接入点是
the wireless access point is
运行在 5 GHz 频段下的时候
operating in the 5GHz band.
才可以连接额外的蓝牙协议
Once iAP2 is connected iOS
一旦 iAP2 协议连接
provides the device transport
iOS 会为设备提供
identifiers so that the head
传输标识符
unit can store the device as a
所以车载系统可以将这一设备保存为
CarPlay device and recognize it
CarPlay 设备
over a different transport when
并且当它之后被重新连接时
it gets reconnected later on.
可以通过不同的传输方式识别出它
The head unit listens to
车载系统遵从
wireless CarPlay update
Wireless CarPlay Update（无线 Carplay 更新）通知
notifications and if CarPlay is
并且如果 Carplay
enabled on device it may choose
在设备上被启用 它可以确认
to confirm whether to proceed
是否继续
with setup for CarPlay.
设置 CarPlay
As we saw earlier, this
如我们之前所看到的
confirmation is only needed if
这一确认步骤仅仅当
the user selected the device
用户从
through the add Bluetooth device
添加蓝牙设备菜单中选择了设备
menus.
才是必须的
As the user initiated pairing
当用户
through Bluetooth settings on
在 iPhone 的蓝牙设置中开启配对
iPhone we see a similar
我们在 iPhone 上可以看到一个类似的
confirmation on iPhone as well.
确认步骤
Of course, neither of those
当然
confirmation dialogs will be
如果用户从 Carplay 特定菜单中
shown if the driver initiated
开启了配对
pairing from CarPlay specific
任何确认会话
menus.
都不会显示出来
Next, let's assume the user
接下来 我们假设用户
confirms on the device first.
先在设备上做出确认
When that happens the device
在这种情况下
requests to receive the wireless
设备会要求接收
credentials of the Wi-Fi access
Wi-Fi 接入点的
point.
无线证书
The head unit must wait for the
车载系统
user confirmation before
在响应之前必须得到
responding.
用户确认
This is the time to get the
此时应该得到
user's consent and if needed,
用户的同意
reconfigure the system for
而且  如果有需要的话
wireless CarPlay.
为无线 Carplay 重新配置系统
Now the user confirms on the
现在 用户同样
native UI as well.
在原始用户界面内做出确认
Then the head unit responds with
之后车载系统
the credentials and iPhone
带着证书做出回应
starts searching for the access
iPhone 开始寻找接入点
point and joins it.
并加入
From now on, exactly ask for
那么之后 正是请求
wired CarPlay.
有线 Carplay
Bonjour discovery runs and once
Bonjour 搜索服务会运行
the device is found the head
一旦设备被找到 车载系统
unit initiates a CarPlay session
就会通过 CarPlay 控制接口
through CarPlay Control API.
开启一个 CarPlay 会话
CarPlay session follows, as well
CarPlay 会话随后开启
as connection establishment for
一并还有
iAP2 over CarPlay.
关于 CarPlay 的 iAP2 协议的建立
Note that at this point iAP2 is
在这时 iAP2 协议
also still connected over
仍然同样是
Bluetooth.
通过蓝牙连接的
Then iPhone sends a disabled
之后 iPhone 会发送一个
Bluetooth command and the head
禁用蓝牙指令
unit must disconnect all
车载系统必须断开所有
Bluetooth connections to this
与这台设备相关的
device.
蓝牙连接
Remember that if the access
请记住 如果
point is operating in the 2.4GHz
接入点是运行在 2.4 GHz 频段下
band Bluetooth needs to be
当有一个活跃的
turned off while there's an
Carplay 会话的时候
active CarPlay session to avoid
为了避免干扰
interference.
蓝牙是需要被关闭的
Now that the screen and video
现在 屏幕显示和视频流
streams are started and the
都已开始
CarPlay UI is visible on the
CarPlay 用户界面也出现在屏幕上
screen voila, CarPlay is running
CarPlay 正在无线运行
All right, now that we saw how
好的 既然我们已经看过了如何
to set up wireless CarPlay
建立无线 CarPlay
here's some general points to
这里有一些
consider.
需要考虑的地方
First, after setup is done the
首先 在设置完成后
CarPlay UI is expected to show
CarPlay 用户界面应该
up.
出现
Then if iPhone is playing music,
之后 如果 iPhone 正在播放音乐
music playback will be set up
音乐回放
through CarPlay.
将会通过 CarPlay 建立
Lastly, the device must be
最后 设备必须
stored as the last connected BT
被保存为最后连接的蓝牙设备
device so that it can be
这样它才能
reconnected automatically later
在之后
on.
自动连接
And with that we can conclude
我们可以结束
the discussion around setup and
对于设置和配对的讨论
pairing and move to actually
并移步
look into how a CarPlay device
深入了解当用户回到车里的时候
is connected when the user
CarPlay 设备
returns to the car.
是怎样重新连接的
When you reconnect for CarPlay
当你要重新连接 CarPlay
you need to take into account
你要考虑到
all devices connected to the
当时所有连接到
system at the moment, as well as
系统的设备 以及
the state of the system before
引擎关闭前
ignition was turned off.
系统的状态
Whether CarPlay is using USB as
无论 CarPlay 是使用 USB 作为传输
the transport or the wireless
或者是无线连接
link it's completely transparent
对于用户而言都是完全清楚的
to the user and depends only on
并且仅仅取决于
how a device is connected to the
设备与车辆是如何连接的
car and in which order the
以及
connections happened.
连接的顺序是什么
After deciding which device to
在决定连接哪一台设备后
connect to make sure the device
请确保设备
still has CarPlay enabled.
仍然开启了 CarPlay
Revert to using legacy
如果 Carplay 处在不可用的状态
technologies if CarPlay is no
请使用
longer available.
老办法
Once the reconnection succeeds
一旦重新连接完成
restore how the user used the
请恢复到上一次
system last time.
用户使用这一系统的状态
If she was listening to FM radio
如果她在听调频收音机
continue playing it.
请让它继续播放
Show the last screen the user
请显示出用户
was looking at either a native
所查看的最后的内容
application or CarPlay.
无论是一个原始应用程序或是 Carplay
The user experience should
用户体验应该
simply continue and follow the
持续并遵从
user's habit.
用户的习惯
Lastly, once a CarPlay session
最后 一旦有一个 Carplay 会话
is running on a device do not
在设备上运行时
interrupt it.
不要打断它
Imagine the driver is listening
请想像司机正在听
to her favorite song or
她最喜欢的歌
navigating and a friend plugs in
或者正在导航时朋友将设备插入
to charge it will be disruptive
来充电
if music all of a sudden resumed
如果突然朋友手机里的音乐开始播放
from the friend's phone.
这是非常有干扰性的
Now let's review some scenarios
现在我们来回顾一些场景
to better understand what it
来更好地理解
means when we say the
当我们说
reconnection depends on the
重新连接取决于
availability and the order of
项目的可用性和顺序
events.
是意味着什么
In all these scenarios, we
在所有这些场景中
assume that the phone has been
假设手机之前已经
previously paired for wireless
配对过
CarPlay and the system has at
无线 CarPlay 并且系统
least one USB port.
有至少一个 USB 接口
We are going to pay attention to
大家请注意
when iPhone was connected over
当 iPhone 通过 USB 连接时
USB, identify a common scenario,
确定一个普通场景
and observe which transport is
并观察哪一种传输方式被用来
used to establish a CarPlay
建立 CarPlay
session.
会话
First, let's look at the
首先 请看
scenario where there is just one
这个场景
iPhone in the car.
只有 一台 iPhone 在车里
The simplest situation is that
最简单的情况就是
the user gets back into the car
用户回到车中
for a short drive and keeps
开车走一小段路
iPhone in the pocket.
并将 iPhone 一直放在口袋里
A morning commute running small
比如早间通勤办一些简单差事的情况
errands would be the perfect
就是非常好的
examples.
例子
As the only available transport
因为唯一可用的传输方式是无线传输
is wireless naturally CarPlay
很自然地
runs wirelessly.
Carplay 也是运行在无线状态下
In the next scenario, the driver
在下一个场景中 司机
plugs in after the drive has
开车后
started.
将手机用线缆连接了
Typical usage here is just
这是个很典型的习惯
realizing that the phone needs
出门后意识到
to be charged after departing.
手机需要充电
In this case, the session has
在这种情况下
already started over wireless
会话已经通过无线方式开启
and since we do not want any
因为我们不想有任何的打扰
interruptions CarPlay remains
CarPlay
over wireless.
会保持无线连接的状态
In the next scenario, the user
在接下来的场景中 用户
simply leaves the phone plugged
将手机用线缆连接并留在车内
in and gets out of the car.
然后下了车
This could be a stopover at the
这可能是要
gas station or simply forgetting
在加油站临时停一下或者就是简单地
the phone in the car.
把手机忘在车里了
Now when the user returns the
当用户回来的时候
device is available to connect
设备可以通过 USB
over both USB and wireless.
或者无线的方式来连接
However, usually the USB stack
然而 通常 USB 层恢复地更快一些
resumes faster so CarPlay is
所以 CarPlay 是
reconnected over USB.
通过 USB 重新连接的
Now let's look at what happens
现在我们来看一下
if the driver plugs in right
如果司机一进入到车内就将手机用线缆连接到车上
after entering the car.
会发生什么
This could be when leaving for a
这可能是要去
longer trip or maybe needing to
长途旅行或者是
charge right away.
需要马上充电
In this case, as the system is
在这种情况下
coming up it will bring up both
系统启动时会同时带动
the USB and wireless stacks.
USB 和无线两种模式
Since the timing will depend
由于对时间的把控是
heavily on the user's behavior
非常依赖于用户习惯的
the CarPlay session will be
CarPlay 会话
started over the first available
会通过第一个可用的
transport.
传输方式连接
If USB is up while BT or Wi-Fi
如果 USB 已连接 然而蓝牙或者 Wi-Fi
are still reconnecting the
还在重新连接
session will end up being over
这个会话会最终通过
USB.
USB 连接
If wireless reconnected before
如果无线模式在
USB then the session will run
USB 连接之前就完成了重新连接
over wireless.
该会话就会在无线模式下运行
In the last scenario, we
在最后一个场景中
consider multiple devices in the
我们考虑
car.
车内有多台设备的情况
The driver might have plugged in
司机可能一进到车里
right after entering the car.
就把手机用线连接了
This could be a road trip with
这可能是跟朋友
friends that need to charge at
去公路旅行时需要充电
some point or want to play music
或者想播放
from their phones.
手机里的音乐
Again, as before, the session
再一次 如同之前一样
will initially start depending
会话最初怎样开始是取决于
on the available transport.
可用的传输方式
Later on, the driver might
过后 司机可能想
decide to change the active
通过使用原始用户界面
CarPlay device using the native
更换活跃的 CarPlay 设备
All right, now let's see how you
好的 现在来看一下
can implement all these
你们如何实现这些
scenarios.
场景
We can start by looking at the
我们可以通过查看
flow for wireless reconnection.
无线重连的流程开始
First, wait until both Bluetooth
首先 等待蓝牙
and the access point are fully
和接入点
operational.
完全启用
Then check that the last
然后检查最后连接的设备
connected device is marked for
是否在车载系统内被标记为
CarPlay on the head unit.
CarPlay 设备
If it is, make sure that there
如果是的话 请确保
is no other active CarPlay
没有其他活跃的 Carplay 会话
session either with the same
不论是与这同一台设备之间
device or with another wired or
还是其它的有线
wireless device.
或者无线设备
If there is no other session
如果没有其它会话了
proceed with connecting iAP2
继续通过蓝牙进行 iAP2 协议连接
Once iAP2 Is connected wait to
一旦 iAP2 协议 连接后
receive a notification that
请等待接收
wireless CarPlay is enabled.
无线 Carplay 启用的通知
If it is wait for the device to
如果已启用 请等待
be discovered and connect.
设备被发现然后连接
When the connect command is
当连接指令发出后
issued iPhone will check which
iPhone 会检查
interfaces are available and
哪个用户界面是可用的
will initiate the session either
并会通过无线或者有线的方式
over wireless or wired.
开始会话
Moving on to USB the flow looks
对于 USB 连接方式 这一流程
fairly similar.
看起来相当类似
You wait until the device gets
你等待设备
connected, you check that there
连接好  你检查一下
is no active session as we do
有没有其它活跃的会话
not want to interrupt it.
因为我们不想干扰到它
If there is none check that
如果没有的话
CarPlay is enabled.
检查 Carplay 是否已启用
Then proceed with your role
接下来进行  Role Switch（角色转换）
switch and selecting a device to
并选择一个设备
connect.
来连接
At this point again, iPhone
在这时 iPhone 会检查
checks if both the wireless and
是否无线和
wired link are available and
有线连接都是可用的
picks one of the two to
并从二者中选择一个
establish the session.
来建立会话
Then last user mode is restored
最后使用过的用户模式会恢复
and the driver is all set.
司机就准备就绪了
In the previous two slides, we
在前两张幻灯片中
saw how to automatically
我们看到了如何自动
reconnect to the last used
重新连接到最后使用的
device.
设备
But what happens if there are
但如果
multiple CarPlay devices in the
有多个 CarPlay 设备在车里
vehicle?
会发生什么
They might be connected just
它们可能是通过
over USB, just paired for
USB 连接的 或者是通过
wireless or both paired for
无线配对的 或者同时由无线配对
wireless and connected over USB.
并通过 USB 连接的
One of those devices will get
这些设备中的一台
reconnected automatically, but
会自动重新连接
as we mentioned before, the
但正如我们之前提到的
native UI lists all devices and
原始用户界面会列出所有的设备
lets the driver change the
并让司机选择更改
active CarPlay device.
活跃的 Carplay 设备
When that happens, the head unit
这时 车载系统
follows the same procedures to
会遵从相同的步骤
reconnect over the available
来通过可用的传输方式
transport.
重新连接
Lastly, let's talk about
最后 我们来讨论一下
reconnecting after a session
在一个会话中断后的
disconnect.
重新连接
CarPlay disconnection might
CarPlay 连接中断的出现
occur for multiple reasons.
可能是由于多种原因
The head unit must be aware why
车载系统必须意识到为什么
the disconnection happened and
发生了连接中断
determine if a reconnect is
并决定是否有必要重新连接
Here are a couple of common
以下是一些常见的场景
scenarios and expected outcome.
和相应的结果
In situations where the user
在用户
unplugs from USB or manually
拔出 USB 线缆的情况下
disconnects from the native UI.
或者手动从原始用户界面断开连接的情况下
No reconnection is needed as
不需要任何的重新连接操作
there was an explicit user
因为这是明确的用户操作
action to terminate the CarPlay
表明用户结束了 Carplay
session.
会话
However, if the phone is no
然而 当手机不再可用的时候
longer reachable for example,
比如
the user walks away, turns off
用户走开了 关掉了
Wi-Fi or anything similar, the
Wi-Fi 或者任何类似的东西
head unit is expected to do a
车载系统应该
fast reconnect to the same
立刻重新连接到
device using CarPlay Control
同一台使用 Carplay 控制接口
API.
的设备
If that fails then proceed with
如果失败了
the Bluetooth reconnect to
继续使用蓝牙重连
reestablish the CarPlay session.
来重新建立 CarPlay 会话
With this we have explored all
这样 我们已经探索过了所有
types of CarPlay connections.
Carplay 连接的类型
Now let's go over some
现在让我们来回顾一些
architectural considerations
结构性的考虑
when designing a wireless
当我们在设计一个无线
CarPlay system.
CarPlay 系统的时候
When designing a wireless
当我们设计一个无线系统时
system, you want to optimize for
你需要为了性能表现
performance.
做出优化
That means that you have to
这意味着
decide which Wi-Fi protocol to
你需要决定去支持那一种 Wi-Fi 协议
support, what configuration to
去使用什么样的配置
use and in which frequency band
以及运行在什么
to operate.
频段下
Next, you need to think about
接下来 你需要考虑
what other wireless technologies
还有什么其它的无线技术
will be used in the vehicle and
会在车内使用
potential interferences.
及其潜在干扰
Services like Internet data or
像互联网数据这样的服务
other in-car applications might
或者其他车内应用程序
also have an impact on the
都有可能
performance.
对性能表现有影响
With all that in mind you need
牢记这些后
to assure that the wireless
你需要确保
performance requirements for
Carplay 无线性能表现的要求
CarPlay are satisfied.
全部都满足了
So, what do we recommend for
那么 关于无线 Carplay
wireless CarPlay?
我们推荐去做些什么呢
First, we really recommend that
首先 我们强烈建议
your wireless access point
你的无线接入点
operates in the 5GHz band.
运行在 5 GHz 频段下
It offers more channels to
它可以提供更多
choose from, it's less prone to
可供选择的频道  更不易
interference, and it is the
被干扰到 同时这是
least congested band.
最不拥挤的频段
Please do use 5GHz whenever
无论何时只要有可能的话
possible.
请一定使用 5 GHz 频段
Even though 2.4GHz is not
尽管不建议使用 2.4 GHz 频段
recommended and is highly
而且它非常
congested in some regulatory
拥挤 在某些监管领域
domains you might have to use
你可能还是需要
it.
使用它
Then you need to be very aware
然后你需要格外注意
of coexistent scenarios and you
同时存在的使用场景
must disable the Bluetooth stack
如果已经有一个
completely while there is an
活跃的 CarPlay 会话
active CarPlay session.
你必须完全禁用蓝牙层级
If you offer LTE connectivity on
如果你提供 LTE Bnad 40 频段的
Band 40 your choices of
连接功能
operating channels become even
那么你的运行频道
more limited.
就更加有限了
Remember if you are designing a
请牢记如果你要设计一个
system which will operate in
运行在双频段下的系统
both bands you need to consider
你需要考虑
how the user experience will be
用户体验会怎样
impacted.
被影响
In 5GHz other Bluetooth devices
在 5 GHz 频段下 其它蓝牙设备
may be paired and connected in
可以并行配对连接
parallel, whereas in 2.4GHz,
然而在 2.4 GHz 频段下
adding or connecting a second
要添加或者连接第二台
Bluetooth device is not
蓝牙设备
possible.
是不可能的
Some systems might choose to
有些系统可能会选择
deploy multiple access points or
部署多个接入点
dual band APs to offer a variety
或者双频段 AP 来提供不同的
of in-car services and
车内服务
applications.
和应用
If these access points are
如果这些接入点
operating in the same frequency
都是运行在同一频段下的
band they need to use different
它们需要使用不同的频段
channels to avoid interference.
来避免干扰
If the access points use the
如果这些接入点使用了
same SSID and password they need
相同的 SSID 和密码 它们需要
to offer the same set of
提供同一套服务
services to prevent inconsistent
来避免不连贯的
experience.
体验
And lastly, using hidden
那么最后 不建议
networks is not recommended for
针对 Carplay 使用
CarPlay.
隐藏网络
Finally, let's look at how to
最后 我们来看一下如果
provide Internet data
为 iPhone 提供
connectivity to iPhone.
互联网数据连接
The head unit communicates the
车载系统
state of the Internet
通过
connectivity dynamically through
Apple Divice IE 以及
the Apple Device IE and through
the Networking IE
the Networking IE.
来动态传达互联网连接状态
Notifications need to descend on
当有改变发生的时候
changes.
需要发送通知
For example, to state that the
例如 要说明
data communication module is
数据通讯模块
available on the system or that
在系统中是可用的 或者
there is a failure with that
这一模块出现了故障
module or that the service
或者其服务合同
contract has expired.
已过期
Temporary loss of connection due
由于信号覆盖不佳造成的
to poor cell coverage does not
短暂连接中断
need to be communicated to
不需要传达给
iPhone.
iPhone
For more information about this
要了解更多关于这一会议的信息
session check out the session
请查看本次会议
website.
的网站
If you're interested in
如果你对开发
developing CarPlay apps check
CarPlay App 有兴趣的话
out the Enabling Your App for
请查看 Enabling Your App for CarPlay（使你的 App 可用于 Carplay）
CarPlay session.
部分的会议
Also, refer to the videos from
也请参考去年的视频
last year for basic information
来了解关于 Carplay
about CarPlay.
的基本信息